So for example this is another thing that we can do. We have these two cubes that we have inside a boronoronefractor.
I think in this case I'm going to subdivide them so they are going to look a little bit more organic right away which is actually quite good.
And you can... this is our way of making like a procedural looking stuff.
Let's see if I remember... no this is not...
Totally messed up but well who cares.
And then I put this inside a volume measure so everything is part of the same shape.
And this is the remeshed version is what I'm going to use as a simulation.
And you can quickly get these weird looking things.
In this case the colliders and a half a half a lot of them.
In this case I think I will benefit from not having this one here like that.
So let's see...
Some moment in frame 22 when it packs up.
I don't know maybe I don't want this cube right now.
I want it to expand as much as it can at least in the edges.
Yeah so I increase this nicely looking armchair.
Of course you have to have a big living room in order to put this chair but well.
And also let's get rid of...
I want this one for the top part.
I don't want it for the bottom part.
Yeah.
It's looking really nice.
Reminds me to a typography inspired piece or something like that.
This is looking sick.
Let's scroll as steel.
I say I still just because I'm used to working animation but yeah this is looking dope.
Cool thing as I always say is that I can just go ahead and going to...
This is going to be B01.
Good.
I can't get that.
I don't want to move them that's why I'm not moving that to the right or the left.
But the cool thing now is that with the boronine fracture I have unlimited variations of these chairs.
So this is actually quite procedural.
See I have another one.
Another one.
And yeah I honestly love this kind of workflows because it's basically you have infinite ways of generating new and new.
Generating new assets.
For example we want to simplify the shapes a little bit.
We can do that.
These shapes by itself are really quite interesting though.
So let's actually try to remove that collider too.
I want it to be full organic.
Yeah it's way too abstract I guess.
Still not bad.
But what you can do.
It's something that I normally do too.
Let me get this blackboard here.
Definitely make it smaller.
What we can do is actually just animate it in white.
So.
Here.
So this way we can make it grow.
And then flatten it a little bit whenever we want.
It creates like this super cozy.
It's a weird looking thing too.
And let's make more variations.
That's.
I love this method.
Confia as fact.
Let's also try to make a new version.
I'm going to try something different.
And instead of using this as our point generator.
Well.
Right away we can actually just use what we had.
So for our normal looking sofa.
Looking cool anyway.
But that's not what I wanted to make.
Let's quickly make.
I want to use the matrix as a source for our.
For our shapes.
But let me actually.
I want to see what I'm doing.
Because as you can see.
And the matrix has a lot of clones.
And that's what's being used to generate our cuts.
And as you can see.
You can also have this.
Also procedural way of creating.
Sorry.
Creating geometry.
But you can.
Rotate it.
You can space them out.
And it's creating a really.
Weird looking.
Look.
For example.
If you add more and one more cuts.
You're only going to.
Need to make them.
I think it's going to break with this.
Too many.
And it will probably.
Don't look that good.
I think.
I think this stuff.
Really benefits from being simple.
Yeah.
But you can add more.
More detail to the simulations.
In this way.
It's looking.
Very cool too.
So let's put some light on.
One of them.