Let's make some cool furniture with simulations.
So I'm going to start by making a plane so we can have a collider there.
I'm going to hide the camera because I don't want that to bother me right now.
Right now what I'm going to do is I'm just going to create something that feels organic and abstract.
Imagine that you enter a museum and you see a big sofa that's in the entrance hall.
So that's what we're going to do.
And then after that maybe we can look at doing something that feels a little more grounded in reality in a way.
Something like an armchair for example.
So what I'm going to do is I'm going to grab a spline.
Let's go to top view.
By the way, I still miss the icons for that stuff.
Let's make a quick spline.
I'm not going to get too much into detail because we'll probably refine it anyway.
Let's go back to perspective.
I don't want to see lights, I don't want to see anything.
Let's move it a little bit towards the middle.
Yeah, it's not looking that bad.
Nothing to worry about at this moment.
So let's flip this bad boy.
Let's add a circle.
And well, we have this.
And you'll think this is useless.
Well, it is now.
Let's try to add some cups.
Sorry, the dog is barking in the background.
So everything is more rounded.
Honestly, I'm not too worried about intersections here because I would probably put this into a borderline fracture anyway.
But I'm worried about this part here.
Let's make it a soft interpolation.
Honestly, I'm just going to tweak it a little bit because...
I don't know. I kind of like it when it collides because once you drop it into the volume measure, it looks like it has some kind of wrinkles in a way.
Yeah, we don't have to worry about it being too close because with the simulation, it's eventually going to expand.
So let's drop this into a borderline fracture.
And yeah, we have this kind of pattern, which is not exactly what we are looking for.
Right now, I'm going to try and use it with this point generator distribution.
I don't want to have a lot of cuts because the more we have, the less realistic it's going to look.
So let's go for three.
And let's offset the fragments a little bit so we have some spacing in between them.
So, okay, I think this can work.
Let's just keep moving forward.
Let's remerge that.
So we are starting to have more quad geometry.
Even though it's not perfect, it will probably work for our purposes.
We could either subdivide it here a bit more.
I think I'm going to actually do both.
And then maybe we need to actually subdivide it here too.
But maybe not as much.
Let's give it a go with this and see how it looks.
So we are going to go and simulate this.
Let's put a cloth of somebody.
Let's try with the cloth.
Because we actually need it to be a balloon.
And we need to add some overpressure so it grows.
Go to frame zero.
I think it works.
This is actually a little bit of a bummer.
If you have this disabled, it won't work.
Okay, looks like shit.
Let's add a collider to the ground.
It's not looking as bad.
Trust me, it could be worse.
I think that maybe we have a lot of overpressure and it's happening too quick maybe.
So maybe we are going to need 75 frames.
Let's try with something that feels subtler for now.
Okay.
Yeah, that's a little bit better.
Actually, you know what?
Maybe it will be worth...
What's going on here?
Okay, this is never going to work.
Well, we have this done.
We'll fix it in a second.
But what I'm going to do is I'm going to remove the gravity.
And we need to check this motherfucker.
So remember everything that I said about that corner looking great and blah blah?
Well, we actually need to fix it.
Okay, let's try again.
Okay, this is better.
Without any gravity, it's going to be just better to simulate it.
But as you can see, things are going away.
It's a fun simulation, but absolutely worthless as it is right now.
So what we need to do is that we need to add some mixed animation.
And what I like to do is I put it by force.
And if you set it to just one, it will try to keep its place.
So as you can see now, everything stays in the same place, which is really cool.
And maybe we can start experimenting with this if we want to get some wrinkles and stuff like that.
Well, we are getting this abstract shape.
Honestly, not a fan of it right now, but one thing that we can and we should do...
First of all, let's put the target length a little bit higher so we get more wrinkles too.
I think this is going to do too much, but we have to try.
Well, yeah, but we start to get some more wrinkles here and there.
It's true that maybe we need some more geometry.
So let's try to actually get rid of the subdivision surface.
We will probably need it later, but once we have simulated.
Of course, more polygons means it's going to be slower, but the resolution of the simulation is going to be more realistic.
Yeah, first frames are looking worse, but we are getting much more detail everywhere.
And this is starting to look much, much cooler.
One thing that we can do actually, it's in order to simulate where people will actually sit.
I like to put a collider on top, which is going to be invisible, but it's going to be useful to create more of a sitting area on top.
And let's say we like it there.
As you can see, this way we are starting to get something that can be actually used as an abstract sofa or something like that.
Probably we have to add an edge here.
That's why it's causing that.
So maybe we can try and add a little bit more fillet just so things are a little bit smoother everywhere.
Let's hide this marker.
Yeah, you can see that part is much better now.
And this stuff can be actually subdivided now.
And we have this kind of organic.
Probably the bottom of it is also looking really cool.
We have these really, really cool shapes with a lot of detail.
And these are looking amazing.
And this can actually be applied to any kind of shape.
I'm just doing it in this abstract way because I found that the results are a little bit cooler.
But yeah, it's a really abstract and cool looking sofa.
I have to say I love it. I really love it.
So the cool thing about this is that it's quite procedural.
So I'm going to duplicate this and make sure that I disable the simulations.
And the cool thing is that we can make whatever we want with it.
So if we want to start moving things around, it's going to crash because it's Cinema 4D.
It's on me, actually. I have a lot of stuff.
So we have the boron refractory, which we can still edit.
And we can try as many different shapes as we want.
Well, this part here is looking really lovely.
Mostly this part here goes back that, but well, probably because of this reason.
So what we can do is actually put this inside a volume...
What am I doing?
Volume builder and a volume measure.
Let's give it more... not space, but resolution.
And we can try and see this, how it looks.
We have more triangles right now, so the simulation is way, way more organic.
But it kind of mimics a growth simulation, which is also really fucking sick.
It's a little bit disgusting, too.
Wow, so sick.
I'm going to grab a still of this.
Lovely. Disgusting, but lovely.
And if we subdivide it, it's going to be a little bit tighter, but let's see.
Yeah, it's a little bit unbearable to work with.
But it creates a really, really organic shape.
And look at this bottom part is looking so sick.
I think it has actually skipped...
Yeah, it has skipped the ground because I forgot to put the collider there.
But it's also cool what it's creating there.
To be fair, it's quite... I have to stop looking at it.
It looks disgusting.
Yeah, too much geometry, but it's all right.
It's all right.
And the cool thing about this technique is that you can apply it to this spline.
You can apply it to some cubes.
But let's see it in a second.
What I'm going to do now is I'm going to try and use this...
Let me see.
I want to make this our collider, too.
So maybe... let's see. Let's see how it works.
Well, they disappear.
Probably once we've added this...
I'm going to put back ours.
The volume measure maybe we need to tweak a little bit.
Especially this one because that's the one that's creating all the wrinkles.
Which again, they are looking good, but probably not what we're looking for at the moment.
They get a little bit lost too quick.
What I'm going to try and do is I'm going to use this circle.
Oh, shit.
It changes.
We can add a plane to make them a little bit bigger.
This is just for testing purposes.
But let's see how it looks.
Again, we have a lot of issues here.
These other parts are looking great because we have these kind of chains that are keeping the shape together.
But let's try, maybe we need to...
Actually, also, let's do one thing.
I'm going to create an instance of this main spline.
And I'm going to replace it with the second one that's creating this.
So that way, if we modify one spline, we just need to do it once.
Let's try and make a more normal looking...
Whatever this is.
Let's disable this too.
And also the remesher, please.
I'm thinking that probably we don't need the remesher here.
Because we are actually putting things inside the...
The whole image, anyway.
You see, it's respecting that shape a little bit.
It's getting fucked up there.
But honestly, I think that's like limitations from Cinema 4D.
It's true that also these guys here don't have a lot of resolution at all.
Maybe they have a little bit more geometry.
It won't be as bad.
But well, to begin with, they are even already colliding.
Disable poise, that's it.
I don't know, I think it's looking really cool.
I love it.
Let's try some other weird stuff.
Let's start to organize things a little bit.
This is going to be B2.
This is B1.
Always remember to disable all your dynamic tags.
Otherwise, everything is going to be simulated.
For example, this stuff.
Can't it be disabled?
That fucking sucks.
Fucking sucks.
Well, I'm going to just remove myself.
And actually, if you remove the volume cursor, that's going to be better.
Otherwise, it's going to calculate it.
And this is the collider that we are using.
This can be global, but I'm going to duplicate it both times for this and this.
Just so I can keep track exactly of everything that's going on.
B1.
Sadly, I need to remove the collider tag.
Let's try to do something that feels a little bit more normal in a way.
Let me reuse this.
The first tag that we were using, I'm going to enable it.
I'm just going to press hit to see how it is.
Your average looking cushion.
Let's put it in a volume cursor.
I'm going to try different shapes.
Let's put this in a symmetry maybe, so we are saving some time.
This looks like shit because it's too low poly.
Actually, right now we are creating a growth effect because we are simulating inside the volume cursor.
This is actually also something cool to check.
You are actually creating a growth effect because we are simulating and then we are applying the volume measure.
It's cool, but I don't think Cinema 4D is there to be able to pull up these simulations.
It's actually quite cool. It can look like a foam simulation.
At this moment it's also colliding with each other because it's actually three different shapes.
The result is actually quite cool, but it's not what I was looking for.
I was looking to modify this as a whole.
The plane right now is not working well for that reason because we have some stuff outside.
Let's try another cube that we are going to put inside a folder.
I'm putting this inside a folder because I like to keep things tidy.
So every time that I put something that I want to subtract, I can just put it inside of the folder and that's going to be much easier to work with.
Cool stuff. That's really cool.
Let's keep adding shapes to our weird looking sofa.
As you can see right now for this process I'm not taking into consideration anything about shapes.
I'm just keeping in mind proportions so I know that this could later on be applied to something real if needed.
There you go. A nice inflated sofa.
Probably we have too much of this audio. Sorry about that.
If you want things to look cleaner you can have these kind of shapes that are looking super fun too.
Otherwise these kind of shapes are really hard to pull up.
I think right now this is not so beautiful but you can tweak things just to make it look a little bit more refined I guess.
Now to be fair, I won't blame anyone but myself because the shape that I'm using is super ugly.
It makes no sense at all.
The proportions are all... well that's why I'm going to tweak it a little bit so we got something that looks a little bit more refined.
Let's try something like this.
I mean this is looking cooler.
Let's add a little bit more pressure.
A little bit of this, a little bit of that.
Love it. This is looking much better.
And now what I'm going to do is I'm going to use these shapes that we have here and I'm going to create some colliders to act like the base of our chair.
So for example if we duplicate these two...
I mean this is going to be hard to give a little context like in real life.
But we can definitely try to make it feel a little bit more grounded in reality.
So yeah, let's do this for now.
Maybe then we can connect things if we need.
Let's see if it doesn't break.
Okay, it broke.
I think it worked at the beginning.
Yeah, but then it totally ignored our...
We have too much pressure going on so let's try with three.
It got absolutely ignored.
Let me try to quickly...
Actually, let me try.
Yeah, I think it wasn't just working at all.
We need to attack for each of them.
Actually this one, I'm going to make it...
And you can see you have this shape inside of this other shape.
It's just looking really cool.
Well, I'm not a super fan of this shape because it looks a little bit stupid to be fair.
But you can go ahead and also...
I think I broke it.
Yeah, I broke it.
I broke it because now this is our initial geometry, but well, it doesn't really matter.
So, for example, maybe what we can do right now, let's say this is our shape.
We can either put it like this or it's going to collide if it goes farther.
But things are going crazy right now.
And we need some more colliders there, that's for sure.
So let's try to bring back the collider.
And I want to bake a shape out of this one.
And I'm going to...
Oops, what's happening here?
Probably we have more colliders everywhere.
Yeah, that sucks.
Yeah, I think that works better.
So maybe we don't want this huge collider.
Let's try and put this in a way so we can create...
Imagine this is a bench.
And I want that part there to be this part here and this part here.
So I can create a sitting area in both places.
Yeah, that's looking good.
And let me get a still of this shape.
Maple and...
Okay, so we have this as our main starting base.
Let's try to fix the geometry a little bit.
Maybe we can put a smooth on it.
And have a little bit more control on those wrinkles.
You can see it was like this.
Maybe the font tag itself could work anyway.
But I think it can be used also.
There's a smoothing deformer.
We have this weird sitting area.
It's looking great.
This bottom part is looking even cooler.
And actually, I just had an idea.
This can actually also be used for 3D printing as the kind of shape that it's creating.
This can be used, for example, as a keyholder.
Okay, I know that I'm not working in scale.
But you can actually...
This is your real-life size keys.
You can actually print this motherfucker and you have a full keyholder for your plot.
As I'm going to put the models there, feel free to do with them whatever you want.
That's what I like about this kind of way of designing things.
I actually don't need to think much.
I'm just experimenting with it.
And whatever that comes out works for me.
If I'm making a sofa, let's say...
I'm always making a sofa just to show the technique.
But if I'm making a sofa and then I come up with this idea...
This is actually a fucking win because it's actually even a cooler idea than the previous one, you know?
Well, yeah.
It's enough for the struggles a little bit.
It's very useful to place things correctly.
But you can see it can be quite a nice thing to have laying around in your flat.
I love it.
But that wasn't what I was planning to show.
I was planning to show how we can actually make this look more comfy.
So, let's make another cube.
And let's make a pillow out of this one.
Let's start with a regular sized one.
I want to use these guys as a collider.
And...
We need more geometry here.
If you select both press ctrl and drag, you will add more segments to each side.
Let's put this as a cloud.
And...
Oops.
Sorry, there's already way too many.
And you create a fillet and then you give this some inflation.
It will struggle because it's too thin.
You give it a little more air.
It still struggles because it's so thin that you need to give it a little bit less thickness.
Let's try with 5.
Okay, yeah.
It's breaking.
Not sure why, but let's find out.
Probably let's try without fillet.
So, let's give it a little bit more segments here.
And we need way more inflation.
Cool.
We have something that starts to look like a cushion.
I want it to be a bit thinner though.
Let me see if I can actually get it to work with fillet.
Because I know that fillet helps...
Well, fuck it.
Well, more geometry means that we need a little bit more inflation too.
I don't know why it's doing that kind of motion.
Maybe this time we need some more other passes.
Let's put the damping a little bit higher.
Yeah, that works better.
So, what I'm going to do is I'm going to actually...
First of all, I'm going to duplicate this motherfucker.
I'm going to put it here.
I'm going to rotate it a little bit to create some more copies.
Let's do something with it.
Well, that one that I scaled down, I'm not sure if I'm going to need to update it.
But let's go to the simulation settings and let's go to, for example, frame 60.
And here we are going to put the gravity to be on.
Two frames before, it's going to be off.
This way we're going to get an inflation animation and then the cushions are going to go down.
So they become cushions then go down.
And this way you can actually, well, I think...
It's not working because we have a collider here.
But I think it's super easy to solidly generate a lot of cushions.
It's not working still because there's probably some other hidden collider over there.
Colliding...
These are not it.
This one.
Okay, now it finally works.
But this is cool because you can actually create a lot of them.
I'm surprised by how well Cinema 4D handles this.
Honestly, I would have never expected it to work that well.
I have a lot of them right now.
It's going to break for a little bit, but as you can see, it's still working quite, quite well.
So now they are inflated and they go down.
You can create like a pillow party.
So with this technique, I created this chair, for example, that you're seeing here on the right.
I just tried to resume it because this is how it was looking.
And I think there's something wrong because this is my base shape.
These are my colliders, which are just basically like a box and a box inside a box.
I think it's currently not looking exactly the same.
Ah, yeah, maybe it doesn't. Let's give it a go.
So I did the same technique. I basically created a base shape, which I was then inflating, and then it's colliding.
But yeah, you know, Cinema 4D has this tendency of tweaking things.
And suddenly when you open a file that you were working on from six months ago, suddenly it's not working.
Yeah, this looks like shit. I'm not sure if the remix is going to get fixed.
It's not. You see? It's like, well, you got a home and want to order online.
But yeah, this kind of shapes and organicness looks really cool to me. I honestly quite love it.
Being able to create these abstract-looking, more organic shapes.