I think I'm going to use this one here in the middle.
It's the one that looks the best.
So let's try to use a backdrop. That's very useful.
I'm honestly going to make a quick, simple setup in a studio setting
because an interior is going to be probably too much for these chairs.
We could, but I don't think it's worth it.
So for example, as you can see, I was simulating in the normal,
regular scale from Cinema 4D.
And now that I'm putting it in the backdrop,
I'm going to actually scale it so it makes sense in real life.
So right now, our main cube is 2 meters,
and I want the piece to be roughly 8 centimeters tops in every way.
So, well, actually, I'm too good. I already made it.
Yeah, let's try to put some...
It's going to be a little bit hard to show
because the shape has too much integral details.
So maybe something that can work.
It's like all the fun stuff is happening here.
So if you do a frontal, it's going to be cool,
but it looks a little bit like an ass too.
So let's try and work with this.
It's hard because it looks a little bit big in terms of scale.
Make this a disk.
I want to create a really flat view.
Not flat, but a strong image of this shape that we have.
Let's put some material.
Honestly, right away, I imagined this motherfucker to be super glossy.
Make it pink.
Let's actually make it super soft,
and then we are going to add a coat layer to it,
so it reflects more.
Now we actually duplicate the light and give it a little bit more.
So we have that.
Maybe we can...
It's looking great.
The shape itself is super weird.
I will admit that it looks like a chewing gum.
Chewing gum, sorry.
Definitely we need to get something like this kind of angle.
But we can try and make it super wide.
I think that's going to be beneficial for this shape.
It looks more underground in a way.
You can make it feel really huge this way.
I think this is the winning angle.
Maybe we can give a little color to the ground.
So this is the weird collection of furniture that we created.
I also have a sofa laying around. Well, a sofa.
Whatever the fuck this is.
Which is also looking great.
But I couldn't fit them all in frame.
So I just removed it.
Hope you guys enjoyed. Let me know if you have any questions.
And I'll see you guys in the next one. Bye bye.